# Ranjini Harihara

550 Bellemont Ct, Johns Creek, GA 30097 | 770-597-5187 | harihara.ranjini@gmail.com

## **Summary:**

2+ Years Experience in Frontend Web Development.

Highl	lights:										
	Experience in designing & developing we	b-b	ased applications using <b>HTML5</b> ,								
	CSS3, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Magento, V										
	Experience in Software development life	-									
	Integration, Testing, Deployment and Maintenance of E-Commerce										
	applications.										
	<ul><li>Experience in hosting websites on GoDaddy and ecowebhosting.</li><li>Experience in using JIRA, Confluence for issue tracking and team collaboration</li></ul>										
	Experience with <b>Agile</b> Methodology, attended <b>Scrum calls</b> .										
	Experience with <b>GIT</b> , <b>Gitlab</b>										
	Knowledge of <b>MVC</b> framework										
	Knowledge of Supply Chain Management and E-Commerce.										
	Ability to <b>Lead</b> a project, <b>Fast Learner</b> , <b>Hi</b>	ghly	y Motivated and Creative with								
_	excellent <b>Communication</b> skills.										
ш	Ability to <b>Multitask</b> and work on multiple	oroj	ects simultaneously.								
Tachi	nical Skills :										
	HTML 5		Wordpross 4.9								
_	I HIML 5	_	Wordpress 4.8								
	CSS 3		Magento 1.9 & 2								
	Bootstrap 4		Drupal 7								
	JavaScript		SQL								
	I jQuery		Search Engine Optimisation								
	I PHP		Photoshop								
	I Brackets		Angular Js								
	I Git		Gitlab								

#### **Education:**

Bachelor of Science: Computer Science

Bangalore University -Bangalore, Karnataka,
India

Post Graduate Diploma in Computer

Application

Bangalore University -Bangalore, Karnataka,
India

National Institute of Computer Technology

# **Experience:**

#### Astral Brands: Magento Frontend Developer (10/29/2017 - Current)

Astrai Brands. Wagento Frontend Developer (10/27/2017 - Current)
☐ Localized and Spruced up existing magento website.
Redesigned wordpress websites according to requirements.
☐ Enhanced Magento website giving attention to details according to company standards and worked on making it responsive.
Extracted Magento static blocks from hooks and hand coded it with HTML and CSS for dynamic yield project.
Magento website Theming.
Styled Turn To extension according to specifications.
Created sliders and carousel Widgets.
RAMA (nonprofit organization): (4/1/2017 to 10/25/2017)  Building responsive websites for non profit organization using HTML5, CSS3, JS, Bootstrap and PHP.
☐ Gathering requirements
Designing creative website template according to client's need using Photoshop
Developing a user friendly, dynamic and responsive website which includes contact forms and paypal payments.
☐ Incorporating SEO's best practices.
Using phpmyAdmin to maintain database.
W. L. C (11/1/2017 4 - 2/21/2017) C2C

#### Web Consultant: (11/1/2015 to 3/31/2017) S3Group - Duluth

	Ma	ana	gec	l C	omp	olete	lifec	:ycle	of	CMS	&	Econ	nmer	ce '	Website	e de	eve	ole	pmen	t.
_	_																			

☐ Participated in client meetings to understand requirements and design options.

0	Carried out acceptance testing on the project deliverables.  Coordinated with offshore development and testing team to ensure quality and timely delivery.
Proje	
-	/www.votrevu.com/: Responsive E-commerce website for French Skin care and m blended cosmetics.
	Base configuration in Magento Ecommerce application
	Theme installation
	Product uploads into the database (bulk and individual)
_	Configurable products and pricing
	cross browser testing
0	Coordinated with senior developers to discuss client requirement and design to outcome.
	uscabinetdepot.com: Responsive B2B E-commerce portal for Cabinet Company Magento 2 application.
•	Participated in business meetings to understand client requirements.
0	Coordinated with offshore developers to discuss client requirement and ensure timely delivery.
	Coordinated with offshore testing team. Wrote test cases for user acceptance testing.
	shawnbratton.com: Responsive CMS Website for Judge Shawn Bratton for electialign using Drupal.
•	conwaysheriff.org : Responsive CMS Website for Sheriff election campaign using

Prepared step by step training Materials for easy learning
☐ Prepared activities to engage student interest and improve understanding of
concepts.
Assessed progress through quizzes and tests.

## **Additional Skills:**

# **Supply chain Management:**

Warehouse Management, WMS/PKMS, ERP

Training:

Inbound, outbound, inventory, wave